ILGWU. David Melman papers, 5780/152
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Mode O'Day: Agreements, Company Exhibits, 1968-1985 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  Arbitration filing, "Points and Authorities in Support of Motion to Reopen the Record to Take Additional Evidence and Declaration of Steven T. Nutter," with attached "exhibit "A" pay stub, exhibit "B" letter from ILG attorney Nutter, exhibit "C' denial by arbitrator; contract agreements apparently used as exhibits in arbitration case: (1) National Association of Blouse Manufacturers, Inc. with the Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers' Union, Local 23-25, (ILGWU) and Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, Local 10 (ILGWU), June 1, 1982- May 31, 1985; (2) New York Coat, Suit, Dress, Rainwear and Allied Workers' Union and ILGWU with New York Coat and Suit Association, Inc., and Infants' Children's & Girls' Sportswear and Coat Association, Inc., 1982-85; (3) New York Skirt and Sportswear Association, Inc., with ILGWU and Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, Local 10 (ILGWU) and Blouse, Skirt and Sportswear Workers' Union, Local 23-25, (ILGWU), 1982-85; (4) Affiliated Dress Manufacturers, Inc., Apparel Manufacturers Association, Inc., with ILGWU and Dressmakers' Joint Council, 1982-85; (5) Lingerie Manufacturers Association of New York, Inc., and Intimate Apparel Workers' Union, Local 62-32 (ILGWU) and Amalgamated Ladies' Garment Cutters' Union, Local 10 (ILGWU), July 1, 1981 to June 30, 1984; (6) Office and Distribution Employees' union, Local 99 (ILGWU) and New York Coat and Suit Association, Inc., and Infants' Children's and Girls' Sportswear and Coat Association, Inc., June 1, 1982-May 31, 1985; (7) repeats # 2; exhibits 8, 10, 12-13, 15-16: master agreement union demands, 1979, 1982, 1983; modification of agreement, 1968, re contribution to health plan
- Mode O'Day: Comparative Agreements, Wages and Benefits, 1982-1986 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  List of quarterly average earnings for individual workers at Mode O'Day's Salt Lake City, San Bernardino, and Hastings plants, May 15, 1984; Gambles Major Medical and Long Term Disability Benefit Program, Sponsored by Wickes Companies, Inc (with hand notation, "Logan, Utah Benefits"); breakdown of seniority of bargaining unit employees; seniority list of individuals, August 1984; memo re retirement fund; analysis of computation of vacation pay, with copies of pay stubs, February 1985; Amalgamated Clothing and Textile Workers' Union (ACTWU) agreement, 9/1/79-8/31/82; printed Teamsters agreement, 1/1/84-12/31/86, agreement between Mode O'Day Company and General Warehousemen's Union, Local 598 I.B.T., 1/1/84-12/32/86, letter from regional director Cornelius Wall referring to agreements, comparing to ILG demands re health plans, wage give-backs; article reprint, "After the Shutdown: The Social and Psychological Consequences of Job Displacement," by Louis A. Ferman, ILR Report, Spring 1981; handwritten notes
- Mode O'Day: Arbitration and Negotiation, 1979-1984 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  List, "Subjects of Arbitration"; notes from negotiation meetings; union demands, June 1979, May 1982, June 1983, August 1984; summary of agreement 1979-82, 1982-83, and 1983-85; talking points for arbitration; company newsletters, Wickes Companies, 1984
- Mode O'Day: Bankruptcy, 1983-1985 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  Notes on program filed in bankruptcy matter; newspaper clippings, Women's Wear Daily re Wickes bankruptcy, 1984; company financial profile, Gamble-Skogmo, 9/11/84; court document, bankruptcy filing, Wickes Companies, 1984
- Smoler Brothers, Wicker Park: Local Agreements, Prattville Division, 1982-1989 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  Dunn & Bradstreet (?) credit report and profile of company and owner; signed agreement with Prattville, 1988; marked-up draft of 1982 agreement, signed 1985; marked-up draft for Herrin, IL, location, 1982; marked-up draft of Lincoln, IL, location,1982; memorandum of agreement acknowledging representation of New York sample room by ILG, setting minimums, 1985; memorandum of agreement with Wabansia location, 1985
- Smoler Brothers, Wicker Park: Master Agreement, 1989 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  Edited drafts and final signed master agreement
- ILGWU Personnel Records: A-D, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  Job applications, salary discussion, payment records
- ILGWU Personnel Records: E-P, 1983-1987 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- ILGWU Personnel Records: R-Z, 1984-1985 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- General Executive Board Meetings: May 31- June 9, 1989 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  Hotel Diplomat, Hollywood, FL. No minutes; invitation to attend GEB meeting on May 31, noting that important convention matters will be discussed; lists of attendees, 10/86 through 4/89; memo from Brent Garren to David Melman re dispute being heard by the Texas-Oklahoma-Arkansas District Council, speculates that loser will want to appeal to the GEB and then to the 1989 convention
- General Executive Board Meetings: October 7-13, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  Centre Sheraton, Montreal. No minutes; note that Pres. Chaikin would not be attending; list of ILG delegates to last two AFL-CIO and IUD conventions; list of GEB members in order of their seniority on the board
- General Executive Board Meetings: January 29-30, 1987 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  City Squire Hotel, New York City. Minutes, "Third Meeting"; contract with hotel, memo re task force on organizing
- General Executive Board Meetings: October 23-24, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Colonnade Hotel, Boston, MA. Minutes, "Second Meeting"; attendee list; list of major topics for discussion; "Decisions Made at 10/86 GEB Meeting," sent to GEB, 11/25/86; memo to exec. VP Wilbur Daniels re decrease in insurance coverage for certain long-term staff members at New Bedford. MA, Local 361, whose hours had been reduced, requests instructions; memo to Personnel Review Committee re Pres. Mazur's request for a meeting re wage policy for office and staff members
- General Executive Board Meetings: March 24-27, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  1710 Broadway, New York City. Minutes, "Eighth Meeting"; handwritten notes from meeting; correspondence with attendees; clipping from Women's Wear Daily 12/17/85 re possible labor law violations by Chinatown apparel contractors; letter from Pres. Sol Chaikin to Gerald Roy, pres., Montreal Joint Council, informing him of his appointment as interim Canadian director; minutes of GEB Committee for Retiree Services, held 11/22/85; brief note re attendees at Finance Committee meeting, held 2/5/86; Health & Safety Liaisons Semi-Annual Progress Report questionnaire; memo re potential liability for malpractice insurance for Union Health Center; memo suggesting a meeting of the Union Sanatorium Association be convened at next GEB committee meeting; amended bylaws of Union Sanatorium Association; proposal by APCO Association for development of Manhattan sites for Unity House; memos and article from JUSTICE re merger of New York local health & welfare funds into one joint board; copy edited transcript of speech delivered at 1986 convention, memo re galleys of draft of proceeding for review; list of GEB officers with notes about retirement; letter of resignation/retirement from union archivist Henoch Mendelsund, 2/27/86; year-to-year comparison of totals of union membership by local and region, 1969-85
- General Executive Board Meetings: December 3-6, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  Diplomat Hotel, Hollywood, FL. Minutes; lists of attendees; report to Education Committee; reports from Field Activities, Import Roll Back Campaign; International Relations; Organization & Field Services; Retiree Services; Union Label; Midwest Region; New England; New Jersey; New York City local 91-105, local 30, local 23-25, New York Coat, Suit, Dress, Rainwear & Allied Workers' Union local 89-22-1; New York State; Pacific Northwest; Philadelphia-South Jersey; Puerto Rico; Western States; from Wilbur Daniels, "T-Shirt Situation Report" re union members mistakenly buying non-union clothes; report on agreements negotiated with Country Miss of Cookville, Personal Sportswear, Kay Windsor, Hapco, Hollister Corp., Vestra Ind., Susan Fashions; press release re textbook scholarship for children of local 23-25 workers, mainly Asian American
- General Executive Board Meetings: January 7-12 [folder 1 of 2], 1985 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  Hotel Diplomat, Hollywood, FL. Minutes, Jan. 7-11, 1985; letters of invitation, list of attendees; list of GEB members and birth dates, managers born 1921 or earlier; correspondence re dissolution or merger of upstate NY locals, letters of resignation by various officers of NYC locals related to reorganization of NY Coat, Suit, Dress, Rainwear and Allied Workers' Union (December 1984); meeting agenda; reports from: Benefit Funds Department; Legal Department; Research (re imports); Central States Region; Eastern Pennsylvania; Midwest Region; New Jersey Region; NYC local 23-25, local 91-105; New York State District; Northeast, Western Pennsylvania & Ohio (also "Final Report, 1984 Rank and File Conference or 'Northeast Department Does A Mock Election'"; also "Health Care for all Pennsylvanians"); Pacific Northwest District Council; Puerto Rico; Southeast Region organizing activities, incl. copy of agreement with Kellwood Company (Grenada, Miss.; facility in Fernwood), news clippings; Upper South; Western States Region
- General Executive Board Meetings: January 7-12 [folder 2 of 2], 1985 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- General Executive Board Meetings: June 24-26, 1985 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  Unity House, PA. Minutes, "Sixth Meeting"; reports from: Education Department; Field Activities, Import Roll Back Campaign; International Relations; Legal; Legislative; Organization & Field Services; Retiree Services; Union Label; Central States Region; Eastern Pennsylvania; Midwest; New England; New York City local 23-25 (Chinatown) and local 91; New York State; Northeast, Western Pennsylvania & Ohio; Pacific Northwest; Puerto Rico, Upper South
- General Executive Board Meetings: September 11-14, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  Unity House, PA. Minutes, "Fourth Meeting"; lists of attendees; invoice from Unity House and memo from Wilbur Daniels questioning items; cards with meeting agenda; letter from U.S. Department of Labor (March 14, 1984) to South Jersey Joint Board Health and Welfare Fund re ERISA violations; reports from: Audit Department, 1983 Financial Report: General Funds by region; International Relations; Research Department re imports (March 10-September 10, 1984); Legislative (?); Organization & Field Services; Retiree Services; Central States Region; New Jersey; New York; Southeast; Southern California; Upper South; report by Stratford Advisory Group (September 1984): "Effectively Investing ILGWU's Financial Assets"
- General Executive Board Meetings: March 11-14, 1984 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  Hyatt Regency Hotel, Atlanta, GA. Minutes, "Third Meeting"; identical minutes except says "Second Meeting"; draft of minutes with cover note, "This is the first part of the GEB meeting from M. Peretsman --- the second half will follow"; handwritten notes "Decisions made at GEB meeting, March, 1984"; letters to and from former president Jimmy Carter declining invitation to speak at GEB meeting; announcement of third meeting, list of attendees
- General Executive Board Meetings: March 22-24, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  1710 Broadway, New York City. No minutes; list of invited attendees; reports from: Central States Region; Eastern Pennsylvania Region; New England; New Jersey (includes newspaper clippings, organizing flyers given to office workers, correspondence with police re leafleting, census of gains & losses of members by local and industry, Dec. 1, 1982- Mar. 1, 1983; letter to AFL-CIO Pres. Lane Kirkland from Director Sol Goldberg re scandal over New Jersey pres. Charles Marciante; correspondence with lawyers); New York City local 62-32, Cutters' Union local 10, New York Coat, Suit, Dress, Rainwear & Allied Workers' Union; New York State; Midwest; Pacific Northwest; Puerto Rico; Southeast; Upper South; Western States
- General Executive Board Meetings: October 7-12, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  Hotel Diplomat, Hollywood, FL. Minutes, "Second Meeting"
- General Executive Board Meetings: June 3, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  Hotel Diplomat, Hollywood, FL. Minutes, "First Meeting"
- General Executive Board Meetings: May 30-31, 1983 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  Hotel Diplomat, Hollywood, FL. Minutes, "Eighth Meeting"
- General Executive Board Meetings: January 5-11, 1982 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  Hotel Diplomat, Hollywood, FL. Minutes, "Fourth Meeting"; list of invited attendees; report from the Central States Region (June–December 1981)
- ILGWU Convention: Planning, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Timetable, checklist of logistics; daily convention schedule; instructions for delegate election procedure; directory of locals; 20-page memorandum to Jay Mazur from Gus Tyler re negative comments he collected during 1986 convention (dated June 25, 1986), with recommendations to make 1989 convention more participatory, with handwritten comments in reaction; memo to Mazur from vice president Susan Cowell endorsing Tyler memo, Sept. 19, 1988; memo to Mazur from John Burke re meeting with Cowell to implement suggested changes, Nov. 4, 1988; memo to Mazur from David Melman re changes and themes for 1989 convention, detailing preparations, suggesting eliminating expensive and unappreciated extravagances; Nov. 4, 1988; letter from Mazur to regional directors re letter to be sent to all delegates endorsing need for dues increase; minutes of several meetings of convention planning committee, Oct. 21, 1985-May 17, 1989, including handwritten notes
- ILGWU Convention: Child Care, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Letter noting that child care will be provided for delegates and staff during convention; related correspondence
- ILGWU Convention: Committee Assignments, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Lists of committees and delegate assignments
- ILGWU Convention: Committee Reports [folder 1 of 2], 1989 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  Reports and recommendations of Appeals Committee; Benefit Programs; Civil Rights and Immigration; Constitution; Contract; Credentials; Education; Finance; Imports; International Affairs; Labor Standards Legislation; Officers' Report; Organization; Political Action; Social and Labor Legislation (comprising an introduction on the erosion of the general welfare under Reagan and Bush, and reports on AIDS; Budget Cuts in Medicare, Medicaid and Social Security; Catastrophic Medical Insurance; Child Care; Commercial Rent Binding Arbitration in New York City; Consumer Affairs Agencies; Corporate Power; Drug Abuse; Equal Rights Amendment; Family and Medical Leave; Foreign Ownership; Homeless; Housing; Long Term Health Care; National Health Care; Rent Control; Reproductive Choice; Taxation of Social Security and Unemployment Benefits; Unemployment Insurance; Weekly Disability Benefits); and Union Label
- ILGWU Convention: Committee Reports [folder 2 of 2], 1989 (Box 6, Folder 5)
- ILGWU Convention: Constitutional Amendments, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  Printed proposed amendments; memos re possible change in convention frequency, list of unions that hold their conventions less often than every three years; memo analyzing other unions' constitutions' use of gender-neutral language; memo re increasing strike benefit, instituting two-tiered dues system; memo to Pres. Mazur re proposed changes; correspondence with ILG attorneys re mandatory retirement clause, Supreme Court ruling re dues by non-members, other matters; handwritten notes
- ILGWU Convention Delegates, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  Printed brochure, "Delegate's Guide 40th Convention" (June 2-9, 1989); printed Original Credential certificate for delegates and alternates; memo re pre-registration forms; memo encouraging full participation of alternates; letter from Mazur to delegates re need for dues increase; correspondence re per diem allowances; computer printout of delegates and guests attending; letters and computer printouts re sergeants-at-arms
- ILGWU Convention Equipment: Computers, Furniture, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  Correspondence with convention contractors
- ILGWU Convention Events: Entertainment, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  Memo to hotel that ILG supports grape boycott on behalf of United Farm Workers, requesting no grapes be served; correspondence and schedule of luncheons, parties, etc.
- ILGWU Convention Events: Organizing and Field Services Department, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  Jobs with Justice rally flyer in support of United Mine Workers strike at the Pittston Co., near Diplomat Hotel, announcing speakers including Jay Mazur; cover letters to non-ILG union officials and academics re video of Pittston rally; memo to organizing directors re mandatory Organization Committee meeting and workshops, staffing of booth; sign-up sheets for workshops in Chinese, Spanish, and English re organizing campaigns; list of volunteer organizers; handwritten notes
- ILGWU Convention: Executive Board Reports, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  Printed General Executive Board Report to the 40th Convention; printed Financial & Statistical Report to the 40th Convention; printed Employer Contributed Benefit Funds Report to the 40th Convention; memo to Pres. Mazur re suggested topics for his speech, reviews content of past convention speeches
- ILGWU Convention: Executive Affair Elections, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  Scripts and cue cards; nomination speech in Spanish and English
- ILGWU Convention: Exhibits, Booths, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  List of booth displays at convention; agenda for meeting on exhibits and workshops; memos to ILG departments; correspondence with convention services provider
- ILGWU Convention: Guests and Retirees, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  Lists of Florida retirees and survivors (widows/widowers), retired vice presidents, guests; correspondence with mayor of Miami; letters of invitation to non-ILG union officials, clergy, arbitrators, etc.
- ILGWU Convention: Hotel, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  Post-convention letters to hotel director of sales, and from hotel president and CEO, re poor physical conditions at hotel; invoices
- ILGWU Convention: Convention Services (Grebelsky, Regal Services), 1989 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  Invoices, correspondence
- ILGWU Convention: Letters of Support (Box 6, Folder 17)
  Letter from U.S. Dept. of Labor Secretary Elizabeth Dole noting need to keep America competitive with the rest of the world; letter from United Paperworkers International Union soliciting message of support on the occasion of its convention, letter from ILG expressing support
- ILGWU Convention: Music, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  Checklist/stage directions for musical performances; contract with Wildlife Music; invoices from and payment records to Malcolm Dodds Music, Wildlife Music, Multi Entertainment, and Jack Faith Music Services; meeting notes re chorus, chorus schedule, report on experience of chorus; clippings re Platters; proposal from Lifeline
- ILGWU Convention: Nurse, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  Correspondence re on-site nursing services; insurance coverage policy certificate
- ILGWU Convention: Photography, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  Invoices, payment records, and correspondence re George Relick Photography and Bert Berinsky; copy of a photo of the General Executive Board (original held in Kheel photo archives)
- ILGWU Convention: Printed Publication, Convention Daily, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  Copies of ON THE MOVE, daily newsletter distributed at convention, days 1-7; correspondence re printing expenses, bids from union printers; memo suggesting improvements to editorial production process; list of printed convention material
- ILGWU Convention: Resolutions, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  Printed "Resolutions Submitted to the 40th Convention" (books 1 & 2); typed list of resolutions submitted to the AFL- CIO convention October 1987; newspaper clipping and memo re resolution urging lifting the ban on trade unionists visiting from socialist countries; two lists of resolutions: those adopted at convention that require action by the general office and those referred to the General Executive Board (GEB); letters to locals requesting resolutions
- ILGWU Convention: Signage, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  Correspondence and invoices from Regal convention services re signs and banners; drafts of letter of agreement for decorating the convention hall and producing a slide show; list of signs; letter to locals requesting signs; copies of photos of decorated hall (originals held in Kheel photo archives)
- ILGWU Convention: Songs, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  Printed THE ILGWU SONG BOOK
- ILGWU Convention: Speakers, Correspondence, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  Memo to General Executive Board soliciting suggestions for speakers, with list of speakers at 1986, 1983, and 1980 conventions; response from vice presidents Susan Cowell and Evelyn Dubrow, with list arranged by ethnic/gender/political and other categories, and analysis of rationale for several; list of speakers at recent conventions of other unions; approved list of possible speakers; lists of status of speaker invitations; correspondence with Larry Kirkman, exec. dir., Labor Institute for Public Affairs, re speakers representing Union Yes campaign (Tyne Daley or Edward Olmos); letter from South African Archbishop Desmond Tutu, declining invitation; letters of invitation to NY Gov. Mario Cuomo, with handwritten note from president Mazur: "This would mean a great deal to our membership. Nearly half of our 1000 delegates will be from New York State"; Sen. Edward Kennedy, with handwritten note from Mazur: "This would mean a great deal to us. President, then Sen. Kennedy spoke to our convention in 1959 and Robert in 1965. Our members have not forgotten the contributions the Kennedys made to this nation…"; Jesse Jackson, with handwritten note: "Our people…worked hard on your campaign and would really appreciate your participation…"; Jack Sheinkman, pres., ACTWU; Shirley Carr, pres., Canadian Labour Congress; Member of Parliament Neil Kinnock; Rep. Henry Gonzalez (note declining invitation); Sen. Barbara Mikulski; Puerto Rican governor Rafael Hernandez-Colon; Dr. Ruth Westheimer; Ann Richards, treasurer of Texas; Norman Hill, pres., A. Philip Randolf Institute (mentions plans for convention celebration of 100th anniversary of Randolf's birth, achievements of black trade unionists); correspondence acknowledging positive response from Lane Kirkland, pres., AFL-CIO; Desmond Sampson, gen. secy., Garment & Allied Workers' Union (South Africa), others; list of escort committees
- ILGWU Convention: Staff, Secretaries, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  Report on Convention '89 Secretarial Pool, detailing poor working conditions: long hours, duplicative effort, confusion, isolation, inadequate equipment, recommendations for future conventions; lists of convention secretarial staff, 1989 and 1986; memos re computer needs
- ILGWU Convention: Stage Directions, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  Daily stage directions for speakers/elections, musicians, concurrent slide show (notes Al Gore)
- ILGWU Convention: Translation Service, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  Contract, invoices, and correspondence re simultaneous translation services with PTL Translating Services; price quote from International Simultaneous Translation Services (USA), Inc.; letter from David Melman to John Hudson, ACTWU, re experience with PTL Translating Services, noting that translation was provided in Spanish, French, and Chinese, "tremendously popular" with delegates, at significantly lower cost than other services quoted; letter to PTL president, noting several hundred delegates used service, first time translation services were used
- ILGWU Convention: Travel Arrangements, 1989 (Box 7, Folder 6)